inter-state.com 2019-04-28

# Privacy - Shop

Inter-State Studio & Publishing Co. Privacy Policy 

Last Updated : May 23, 2018 

By accessing and using the Site, you agree to be bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy.  This Privacy Policy is between you and Inter-State Studio & Publishing Co. (“Company”, “us” or “we”).  Inter-State Studio & Publishing Co. is a trusted provider of photographic products and services to communities, schools and families throughout the United States.  At Inter-State, we are sensitive to the privacy concerns of visitors to our websites.  Please read this Privacy Policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect, disclose or otherwise handle information collected from users of our website, located at [https://www.inter-state.com/](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.inter-state.com/&sa=D&ust=1527184303015000)[ ](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.inter-state.com/&sa=D&ust=1527184303015000), and any other online features, tools and resources we provide (collectively, the “Site”). 

We keep this Privacy Policy posted on the Site, and you should review it frequently as it may change from time to time.  ANY CHANGES WILL BE EFFECTIVE IMMEDIATELY UPON THE POSTING OF THE REVISED PRIVACY POLICY. BY ACCESSING AND USING OUR SITE, YOU ARE CONSENTING TO THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY.  

Please remember that this Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by our Site. We are not responsible for the privacy of any information you reveal or post in any public forum (e.g., message board, blog, chatroom or social media site). 

What information do we collect from the people that visit our Site? 

Our Site has the ability to collect two types of information from and about you: personally identifiable information (“PII”) and non-personally identifiable information.  We collect this information: (a) directly from you when you provide it to us; and/or (b) automatically as you navigate through our Site. 

Personally Identifiable Information : Our definition of PII includes any information that may be used to specifically identify you, such as your name, postal and email addresses, phone number, or credit card information.  In certain circumstances, we may request, allow or otherwise provide you an opportunity to submit your PII in connection with some aspect of our Site. When ordering or registering on our Site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, mailing address, phone number, credit card information or other details to help you with your experience. We may also ask for your child’s name, their teacher or coach, and grade or team.  Certain information may not be PII when standing alone (e.g., your age), but may become so when combined with other information (e.g., your age and name). Whether or not you provide this information is your choice; however, in many instances this type of information is required to participate in the particular activity or service, realize a benefit we may offer, or gain access to certain content through our Site. 

Non-Personal Information: Our definition of non-personal information is any information that does not specifically identify you. Non-personal information can include certain PII that has been de-identified; that is, information that no longer reveals your specific identity. We obtain non-personal information about you from information that you provide us, either separately or together with your PII. This information can include, among other things: your IP address or other unique identifiers that are automatically assigned to your computer, mobile or other device used to access the Site; the type of browser you are using (e.g., Internet Explorer, Firefox, Safari, etc.); the third party website from which your visit originated; the operating system you are using (e.g., Vista, Windows XP, Mac OS, etc.); the domain name of your Internet service provider; the search terms you use on our Site; the specific areas within our Site that you visit; information collected through cookies, pixel tags and other technologies and the time of day and duration of your visits. 

When you submit information to us through any of our Site, you should be aware that your information is transmitted across the Internet and that no method of transmission over the Internet is 100% secure. Although we take reasonable security measures to protect your information when we receive it, you also need to ensure you take appropriate steps to protect your information. 

If you disclose any PII relating to other people to us or to our service providers in connection with the services, you represent that you have the authority to do so and to permit us to use the information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

When do we collect information? 

We and our service providers collect information from you when you register on our Site, place an order, subscribe to a newsletter, respond to a survey, fill out a form, or enter information on our Site.  We may also collect certain non-personal information from you when you access or navigate through our Site.  In addition, we may receive information about you from other third party sources, including but not limited to, your school, and social media platforms.  In addition, if you elect to connect your social media account to your account on the Site, certain PII from your social media account will be shared with us, which may include PII that is part of your profile.  We also collect PII from offline resources, such as when you attend one of our trade shows.  

How do we use your information? 

We and our service providers may use information about you when you register, make a purchase, respond to a survey or marketing communication, access or navigate through the Site, or use certain other Site features. 

The information collected through our Site is generally used to fulfill our legitimate business interests including: fulfilling your requests for our products and services, to respond to your inquiries about our offerings, to personalize your online experience, and in other ways naturally associated with the circumstances in which you provided the information.  We may also use this information to later contact you for a variety of reasons, such as customer service, offering you other products or services that we believe may be of interest to you, to send administrative information to you, such as changes to our terms, conditions and policies, or to communicate with you about content or other information you have posted or shared with us via our Site. We may use the non-personally identifiable information that we receive in a variety of ways, including but not limited to administering the Site, helping us analyze site traffic, understanding customer needs and trends, carrying out targeted promotional activities, improving the quality of the pages that make up our Site, gathering broad demographic information, and  improving our Site. We may use non-personal information about you by itself or aggregate it with information we have obtained from others. We may share non-personal information about you with our affiliated companies and/or third parties to achieve these objectives and others.  We may share your PII with affiliated companies and third parties including, but not limited to, our co-promotional partners, list rental/purchasing agencies, contractors, vendors, consultants and professional advisors to the extent necessary for them to perform services on our behalf, and persons or entities with whom we have marketing, business, or other relationships, including but not limited to yearbook publishers.  In addition, by connecting your account on the Site with your social media account, you authorize us to share information with your social media account provider, and you understand that the use of the information we share will be governed by the social media provider’s privacy policy.  In response to a legal process or law enforcement request, including requests made by authorities outside your country of residence we may disclose PII. We also may disclose PII if we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or as otherwise required by law, which may include laws outside your country of residence. 

In addition to the foregoing, we may use your PII or collected non-personal information as follows: 

  * To provide you with information or services or process transactions that you have requested or agreed to receive, including to send you electronic newsletters, or to provide you with special offers or promotional materials on behalf of us or third parties; 
  * To process your registration with the Site, including verifying your information is valid; 
  * To enable you to participate in a variety of the Site’s features, such as online or mobile entry sweepstakes, contests, surveys or other promotions; 
  * To contact you with regard to your use of the Site and, in our discretion, changes to the Site and related policies; 
  * For inclusion in our data analytics;  
  * To protect or defend our legal rights or property, our Site, or other users; and 
  * For purposes of disclosure or transfer to a third party in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer, or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings). 

Information from your Mobile Device 

We may also use technologies, such as location based information, to provide you with tailored information and features as you use our Site.  When you access the Site on your mobile device (“Mobile Device”), we may obtain information from your Mobile Device about the type of Mobile Device you are using. We may use this information to notify you of features and products that may be available on your Mobile Device. Certain features may require our collection of the phone number of your Mobile Device. We may link that phone number to the Mobile Device identification information, but will not use that number for telemarketing. In addition, some mobile network providers (“Mobile Provider”) in the U.S. are required to use technology that tracks the physical location of Mobile Devices that use their service. Depending on your Mobile Provider and Mobile Device, we may automatically receive this information. If we begin to offer services that use this tracking (“pinpointing”) information, we will obtain your consent (an opt-in) before using the information. After obtaining such consent, we may use and store this information to provide location-based services, including location-targeted advertising.   Most Mobile Devices provide users with the ability to disable location services. These controls are usually located in the Mobile Device's settings menu. If you have questions about how to disable your Mobile Device's location services, we recommend you contact your Mobile Provider or your Mobile Device manufacturer. 

Picture Day & Yearbook Notifications 

When you sign up for Picture Day or Yearbook Notifications through the Site, your email address will be used only for notification of important events and dates (such as when your school’s picture date is occurring, or when pictures are available to order). We will not use your information provided for Picture Day or Yearbook Notifications for any other marketing activity. 

How do we protect information? 

Our Site is scanned on a regular basis for potential security vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our Site as safe as possible. 

Furthermore, your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. 

At all of the appropriate stages, we implement a variety of security measures when a user places an order or enters, submits, or accesses their information to maintain the safety of your personal information. 

All payment transactions are processed through a gateway provider and are never stored or processed on our servers. 

Credit cards are accepted, but the credit card account information is never stored on Inter-State systems. We partner with both PayPal and Stripe, two of the largest and most trusted names in the online payment processing business, to process payments. If you wish to make a payment, your information may be collected by such vendors and will be subject to the respective vendor’s privacy policy, rather than this Privacy Policy. 

Please be advised that while we strive to protect your PII and privacy, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you disclose or transmit to us online and are not responsible for the theft, destruction, or inadvertent disclosure of your PII. 

Do we use 'cookies'? 

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about Site traffic and Site interaction so that we can offer better Site experiences and tools in the future. We use cookies to: 

  * Remember and process the items in the shopping cart. 
  * Understand and save user preferences for future visits. 
  * Keep track of advertisements. 
  * Compile aggregate data about Site traffic and Site interactions in order to offer better Site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third-party services that track this information on our behalf. 

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Chrome or Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser's Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.  

If you disable cookies, some features will be disabled. Your site experience could be less efficient and some of our services will not function properly.  However, you can still place orders. 

Other Information Collection Methods We May Use 

In addition to cookies, a few of the other information collection methods we may use include the following: 

Web Beacons.  “Web beacons” are small graphic images or other web programming code that may be included in our Site pages. Web beacons are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of users of our Site pages.  Unlike cookies, which are typically stored on your computer or mobile device’s hard drive, web beacons are embedded invisibly on web pages. Web beacons or similar technologies help us better manage content on our Site by informing us what content is effective, counting the number of users of the Site, monitoring how users navigate the Site, or counting how many e-mails, articles or links  were actually opened or viewed. 

Embedded Scripts. An “embedded script” is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with the Site, such as the links you click on. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your computer, mobile or other device from our server or a third party service provider. 

Web Traffic and Web Performance Analytics.  We may also collect information using a variety of reports from web traffic and web performance analytics companies to improve our Site. This information allows us to better understand users of the Site, and to customize the Site while also tracking our success at reaching new audiences. This Privacy Policy does not govern the ability of any third party analytics company to use and share information collected by such company. 

IP Addresses. An IP address is a number that is assigned to your computer, mobile or other computing device whenever you are surfing the Internet. Web servers (computers that "serve up" web pages) automatically identify your computer or other computing device by its IP address. When users request pages from our website, our servers may log their IP addresses. We may collect IP addresses for the following purposes, among others: system administration, to report non-personal aggregate information to others, and to track the use of our Site.  We may derive your approximate location from your IP address.  

Email Communications. If you send us an email with questions or comments, we may use your PII to respond to your questions or comments, and we may save your questions or comments for future reference. For security reasons, we do not recommend that you send non-public personal information, such as passwords, credit card information, social security numbers, or bank account information, to us by email. In certain instances, we may provide you with the option to set your preferences for receiving email communications from us; that is, agree to some communications but not others. We reserve the right to send you transactional emails such as customer service communications. 

Third-party Disclosure 

Except as otherwise expressly disclosed in this Privacy Policy, we will never sell or trade your PII or information about your buying history.   

Third-party Services 

This Privacy Policy does not address, and we are not responsible for the privacy, information or other practices of any third parties, including any third party operating any website or service to which the services link.  The inclusion of a link on the services does not imply endorsement of the linked site or service by us or by our affiliates.

In addition, we are not responsible for the information, collection, use, disclosure or security policies or practices of other organizations, such as Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Apple, Google, Microsoft, RIM or any other app developer, app provider, social media platform provider, operating system provider, wireless service provider or device manufacturer, including with respect to any PII you disclose to other organizations through or in connection with mobile apps.  . 

Google

Google's advertising requirements can be summed up by Google's Advertising Principles. 

They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. [https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en ](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl%3Den&sa=D&ust=1527184303027000)

We use Google AdWords Advertising on our Site. 

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our Site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our Site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy (https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en). 

We have implemented the following: 

  * Remarketing with Google AdWords 
  * Google Display Network Impression Reporting 
  * Demographics and Interests Reporting 

We, along with third-party vendors such as Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website. 

Opting out of Google advertisements: 

Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page (https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en). Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising initiative opt out page or permanently using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on. 

California Online Privacy Protection Act 

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law's reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. - See more at: [http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf](https://www.google.com/url?q=http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/%23sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf&sa=D&ust=1527184303029000)[ ](https://www.google.com/url?q=http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/%23sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf&sa=D&ust=1527184303029000)

According to CalOPPA we agree to the following: 

Users can visit our Site anonymously. 

Once this Privacy Policy is created, we will add a link to it on our homepage or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our Site. 

Our Privacy Policy link includes the word 'Privacy' and can be easily be found on the page specified above. 

Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes: 

  * On our Privacy Policy Page 

Users are able to change their personal information: 

  * By emailing us 
  * Logging into their account 

Your California Privacy Rights 

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits Users that are residents of California to request the following information regarding our disclosure of your personal information to third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes:  (i) a list of certain categories of personally identifiable information that we have disclosed to certain third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, (ii) the identity of certain third parties that received personally identifiable information from us for their direct marketing purposes during that calendar year, and (iii) examples of the products or services marketed (if we have that information).  If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please email us at  [issnet@inter-state.com](mailto:issnet@inter-state.com) or write us at the address below.  

Your Rights 

We provide you with access to and the ability to amend, erase, export (i.e. data portability), or object to or restrict PII provided by you through contacting the following email address: [issnet@inter-state.com](mailto:issnet@inter-state.com). We will promptly review all such requests in accordance with applicable laws.  In addition, we provide other opt-out features, as described below, that enable you to exercise your right to opt-out of receiving marketing-related emails from us on a going-forward basis.  

How does our Site handle do not track signals? 

We do not honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place. 

User-Generated Content and Public Forums 

The Site may offer publicly accessible community forums or other ways to permit you to submit ideas, photographs, user profiles, writings, recordings, computer graphics, pictures, data, questions, comments, suggestions or other content, including PII (collectively, "User Content"). We or others may reproduce, publish, distribute or otherwise use User Content online or offline in any media or format (currently existing or hereafter developed). Others may have access to this User Content and may have the ability to share it with third parties across the Internet. You should be aware that any User Content you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. Thus, please think carefully before deciding what information you share, including PII, in connection with your User Content . Please note that Company does not control who will have access to the information that you choose to make public, and cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy or keep it secure. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any information that you disclose publicly, share with others or otherwise upload. We are not responsible for the accuracy, use or misuse of any content or information that you disclose or receive. To request removal of your User Content from our community forum or similar features, contact us as set forth below. 

No PII from Children

We are committed to protecting the privacy of children.  Our Site is not designed for or directed to children under the age of 13.  We do not specifically market to children under 13.We do not collect PII from any person we actually know is under the age of 13.  We urge all parents or guardians to participate in their children’s exploration of the Internet, and to teach their children about protecting their PII while online.  If you use the Site, you hereby represent and warrant that you are at least 13 years of age. In compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (see below), any information we receive from users we believe to be under the age of 13 will be purged from our database. 

COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act) 

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation's consumer protection agency, enforces COPPA , which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children's privacy and safety online. 

Images are only available online for viewing by entering a unique and secure code assigned to each student after pictures are taken.  The unique alphanumeric student code is provided to the authorized parent(s) distributed through the school. 

Pictures may also be purchased before picture day with a school code. School codes can be looked up online but do not display identifiable information. Ordering using this code requires the user to enter student, grade and teacher name for purposes of matching orders with the correct picture. Model images are only displayed when ordering with this type of order code.  Pictures purchased through this process are only shipped to the school and distributed by the school to the student. 

CAN SPAM Act 

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations. 

We collect your email address in order to: 

  * Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions. 
  * Process orders and to send information and updates pertaining to orders. 
  * We may also send you additional information related to your product and/or service. 
  * Market to our mailing list or continue to send emails to our clients after the original transaction has occurred. 

To be in accordance with CANSPAM we agree to the following: 

  * To NOT use false or misleading subjects or email addresses. 
  * Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way. 
  * Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters. 
  * Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used. 
  * Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly. 
  * Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email. 

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe or opt-out from receiving future emails or promotional communications from us, you can email us at [issnet@inter-state.com](mailto:issnet@inter-state.com)[ ](mailto:issnet@inter-state.com). 

Follow the instructions at the bottom of each email and we will promptly remove you from ALL correspondence.  

Retention of Information

We will retain information about you for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes for which the information about you has been collected as outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required by law or is advisable in light of our legal position.

Contacting Us 

If there are any questions regarding this Privacy Policy you may contact us using the information below. 

3500 Snyder Avenue 

Sedalia, Missouri 65301 

USA

800-821-7923 

Email: [issnet@inter-state.com](mailto:issnet@inter-state.com)

Jurisdiction 

The Site is hosted in the United States and is governed by United States law. If you are using the Site from outside the United States, please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored and processed in the United States where our servers are located and our central database is operated. The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country. By using the Site, you consent to your information being transferred to our facilities and to the facilities of those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Privacy Policy. 

Sole Statement 

This Privacy Policy as posted on our Site at https://www.inter-state.com/Policy is the sole statement of our privacy policy with respect to the Site, and no summary, modification, restatement or other version thereof, or other privacy statement or policy, in any form, is valid unless we post a new or revised policy. 

Effective Date 

This Privacy Policy is effective as of May 23, 2018. 

63491054.8
